Sanjida Afreen

sanjidaaf@outlook.com | https://sanjidaa.carrd.co/ (587)-973-2276 | Toronto, ON (Open to Relocation)

PROFILE OVERVIEW

Highly skilled data analyst with 2 years of experience in developing advanced Power BI dashboards, application configuration, and data integration. Proven ability to troubleshoot application and integration issues, manage master data for new business needs. Strong background in data analytics, visualization, and reporting,

SKILLS

- Data Visualization: Power BI, Tableau, DAX
- Data Analytics: SQL, Python
- Languages: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, Python, SQL
- Developer Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Git, MySQL, JUnit, Node, Power Query
- Project Management: RPA and Power BI development, Agile methodologies

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Honours Bachelor of Science, Computer Science | York University

Toronto, ON | Apr 2024

Achievements: Dean's Honour Roll 2023-2024

Relevant Courses: Database Management System, Big Data Systems, Computer Network Protocols and Applications

Additional Certifications: Google Cybersecurity Professional, **Microsoft** Cybersecurity Analyst Professional, Developing Serverless Solutions on **AWS**, NoSQL and DBaaS 101, **DevOps** on AWS, Scrum Master, SAP Professional Fundamentals

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst - Program Assistant | York University

Toronto, ON | Mar 2024 – Jun 2024

- Designed and implemented 5 advanced **Power BI** dashboards, enhancing feedback analysis efficiency by 40%, tracking student employment trends over 5 years to highlight a 700% program growth, and boosting job posting visibility by 25%.
- Conducted Microsoft Forms to collect detailed insights on student and employer satisfaction, utilizing Microsoft Excel Power Query for data transformation and DAX for sophisticated data modeling and analysis.
- Created and maintained SharePoint sites and lists as data sources for Power BI dashboards, enabling nightly refresh
 and automation to ensure up-to-date and accurate reporting.

Data Analyst Intern | TC Energy

Calgary, AB | May 2022 – Apr 2023

- Built 6 **Power BI** dashboards handling over **3M** rows per dataset in collaboration with the Product Delivery team and integrated data from **Amazon Redshift** for enhanced performance.
- Mastered **DAX**, **SQL**, and **Power Query** to boost data analysis and visualization efficiency.
- Resolved over 80 IT service requests via ServiceNow, improving response times and user satisfaction, with proficiency in QA testing and validation environments.
- Developed Canvas and Model-Driven **Power Apps** for streamlining licensing processes for **Liquid Pipelines** business, improving their efficiency by 40% through **PowerAutomate** workflow solutions.
- Ensured high data security in Power Platform development, aligning with industry compliance standards.
- Integrated multiple data sources, including **Dataverse** and **SharePoint** to deliver enhanced and comprehensive data-driven user experiences.

Cloud Developer Intern | *TC Energy*

Calgary, AB | Jan 2022 - May 2022

- Developed applications using **Python**, leveraging **AWS services** including Glue, Amplify, Lambda, CloudWatch, S3, and OpenSearch that saved the business over \$1M.
- Followed **Agile** methodologies and **Azure DevOps** for secure project management and documentation.
- Improved code quality and reduced post-production issues by 20% through Pytest framework.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Job Posting Analysis Dashboard https://github.com/Sanjida-a/JobPostingAnalysis

June 2024

- Transformed and analyzed raw job postings data using **Python** and **Power Query Editor**, ensuring consistency.
- Built automated ETL pipelines, storing data in SharePoint and importing it as a web data source for further processing.
- Utilized ChatGPT-40 to analyze and categorize job skills and responsibilities, creating meaningful groupings.
- Developed interactive Power BI dashboards for stakeholders, featuring real-time data insights and key performance metrics.
- Implemented DAX queries to calculate metrics such as the count of positions and seasonal/academic year categorizations.

- Developed an executive sales report for sales managers using **Power BI**, featuring daily updates and filters for real-time insights.
- Extracted and transformed data using SQL, SQL Server Management Studio, and Microsoft Excel.
- Designed a comprehensive data model in Power BI using DAX, connecting sales and budget data for detailed analysis.
- Visualized business proposal, user stories and profiles using Canva for clarity and stakeholder alignment.

LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES

Co-op Program Assistant

Mar 2024 - Jun 2024

Toronto, ON

York University

- Organized a welcome event for 75+ students with 98% turnout; managed budgeting and planning.
- Created an FAQ section on the program website by analyzing question patterns from hosting drop-in sessions, enhancing student resources and support.
- Managed and moderated a Discord channel, facilitating student engagement and providing real-time assistance.

Community Co-Chair of Student Committee

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

Calgary, AB

TC Energy

- Led four major events with over 92 attendees each, enhancing student internship experiences with over 90% turnout.
- Managed weekly planning sessions, handled \$1,500 in budget proposals, and coordinated event logistics across subcommittees.